Laurence Picken Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, circa 1923-2000 (Box 58-62, 65)
  Manuscript and printed scores of original Picken compositions and transcriptions of traditional East Asian music.
  Arranged alphabetically by title of work or folder title.
  - Original Compositions
    - Canon, waltz and jig (Box-folder 58/1)
    - Composition sketchbooks, 1923-1927 (Box-folder 58/2)
    - Composition sketchbooks, 1928-1936 (Box-folder 58/3)
    - Compositions and sketches (Box-folder 58/4)
    - Concert for two pianos (Box-folder 58/5)
    - Five songs 1934 (Box-folder 59/1)
    - Four songs (Box-folder 59/2)
    - Jabuke and Groždja (Box-folder 59/3)
    - Moralité du petit chaperon rouge (Box-folder 59/4)
    - Prelude to foreign parts (Box-folder 59/5)
    - Les Saintes Maries de la mer (Box-folder 59/6)
    - Sonata movement: Slovenja (Box-folder 59/7)
    - Sonatina (Box-folder 59/8)
  - Transcriptions
    - "The Emperor destroys the military formation" (Box-folder 60/1-2)
    - Folk dances choreographed and notated by Liu Fengxue Essen (1971), under Albrecht Knust (Box-folder 60/3)
    - "Haguga no fue-fu" (Marett) (Box-folder 60/4)
    - "Korean court dance" (Siyong mubo) (Box-folder 65/1)
    - "Lion dance" (Box-folder 60/5-6)
    - Miscellaneous transcriptions (Box-folder 61/1-3)
    - "Music for a thousand autumns" (Box-folder 61/4, 65/2)
    - "Myit-zu thaká nat-pàn Bwe" (Box-folder 65/3)
    - "Namguan" (Box-folder 61/5)
    - "O-dai hajinraku" (Box-folder 65/4-6)
    - "Occidental diversions around an Oriental tune" (Albright) (Box-folder 61/6)
    - "Sandai-en" (Arthur Cooper's lecture) (Box-folder 62/1)
    - "Shi Jing" (Box-folder 62/2)
    - "T'ai P'ing Yüeh/Taiheiraku" (Box-folder 62/3)
    - "Toraden" (Box-folder 62/4)
    - "Tsuwano" (Box-folder 60/1-2)
    - Walker, Robert compositions (Box-folder 61/7)
    - "Waves of the blue sea" (Box-folder 65/7)
    - "The wine is clear" (Box-folder 62/6)
    - Wolpert, Rembrandt F., 1975 (Box-folder 61/8)
- Photographs, circa 1930-circa 1990 (Box 63, 65)
  Individual and group portraits, musical instruments, world music performances, and other images. Includes negatives.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Instruments and performers (Box-folder 63/1-6)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 63/7-8)
  - Picken, alone or with others, 1930s-1960s (Box-folder 65/8)
  - Stages making a Shō reed (Box-folder 65/9)